all right well good afternoon everybody
没事好，大家下午好
good to see you welcome welcome to all
很高兴见到你欢迎欢迎所有
those students watching on video as well
这些学生观看视频，以及
before we start we were talking about
在我们开始之前，我们都在谈论
joinable and detached threads and you
可连接和分离线程和你
asked the question about why you would
问你为什么会问题
ever want to have threads running and
曾经 希望有正在运行的线程和
non detached mode you know why you'd
非分离模式，你知道为什么你会
ever run want to have them run enjoyable
曾经遇到想要让他们跑过瘾
and I didn't give you a very good answer
我没有给你 一个很好的答案
so I want to try to to answer that for
所以我想 尝试回答 这个问题的
you better turns out there's an
你最好证明有一个
important class of sort of parallel
重要的一类排序平行的
programming there's an important
节目有一个很重要
parallel programming model called fork
称为叉并行编程模型
and join where program consists of a
并加入其中的计划包括的
series of phases in each things in each
在每个每个事物一系列阶段
phase you have a worker or a master
阶段，你有一个工人或 主
sorry and it creates a bunch of worker
对不起，它创造了一堆工人
threads and then each of those worker
线程， 然后将每个那些工人
threads sells some part of the problem
螺纹销售问题的某些部分
for that phase like so maybe you take
像这样也许你采取这一阶段
your data structure and you break it up
你的数据结构，你打破它
into chunks and then each thread updates
成 块，然后每个线程 更新
the its own chunk of that data structure
该数据结构的它自己的块
for whatever reason the master then has
无论出于何种 原因主遂将
to wait for the work of threads to
等待线程的工作
finish before it can go on to the next
完成才可以继续到下一个
phase so it it does enjoy so this is
阶段，因此它不喜欢，所以这是
called the fork and then it waits for
所谓的叉，然后等待
all the threads to finish by doing a
所有线程做一个完成
join ok so this is called this is called
加盟好了，所以这 就是所谓的这个叫
the fork and this is called the join and
叉， 这就是所谓的加盟，
only when all of the threads have
只有当所有的线程都
finished can it go and do the next do
完成了它可以去做下一个 DO
the next phase
下一阶段
okay so this this model is really
好了，所以这这种模式是 真的
important in things like scientific
等东西的科学重要
computing where you might you're
计算，你可能会很
simulating some domain you're simulating
模拟一些你在模拟域
nature so you represent that at some
自然 ，所以你 表示一些
domain like maybe you're simulating how
域一样，也许你如何模拟
heat flows over a plate you know metal
热过度，你知道的板金属流动
plate and so you might might have these
板，所以你可能会拥有这些
workers you might petition the domain
工人可能会上访域
amongst a set of those workers and then
集合之中的 工人，然后
each one of these phases is a time step
这些阶段的每一个是一个时间步长
and then so once once all the workers
然后所以一旦当所有的工人
have finished a time step then they can
已经 完成了一个时间步长那么他们可以
advance to the next time step and so
前进到 下一个 时间步长等
sorry I don't know why I didn't think of
对不起，我不知道 为什么我没有想到的
it that's a that's an important reason
它这是一个这是一个重要的原因
why you don't this okay so we saw we've
为什么你不这样行吗，所以我们看到了 ，我们已经
seen the threaded threaded programs are
看到螺纹螺纹程序
are nice because you think you can share
是不错的，因为你认为你可以分享
all the global variables but the sharing
所有的全局变量，但共享
can can have unintended consequences so
可以能产生意想不到的后果如此
somehow we need a mechanism where we can
不知何故，我们需要一种机制，在这里 我们可以
control how the flows of each individual
控制每个单独的如何流
thread are interleaved so that bad
线程是交错的，这样不好
things don't happen when we share data
当我们共享数据的事情不会发生
structures okay so this this process of
结构好了，所以这个 的 过程
controlling the the interleaving is
控制的交织
called synchronization so we're going to
所谓同步，所以我们打算
look at techniques that you can use to
看，你可以 用它来 技术
write correct threaded programs by
通过写入正确的线程程序
properly synchronizing them now first
现在正确同步他们先
though we need to have a clear idea so
虽然我们需要有一个清晰的思路，从而
sharing is the issue right if we have
共享是问题的权利，如果我们有
threads that aren't sharing any
线程不 共享任何
resources then there's no problem right
资源那么就没有 问题 吧
that we saw this when we looked at it
我们看到这个的时候，我们看着它
processes there's no shared data
处理没有共享数据
structures of processes so we processes
流程结构，所以我们 处理
just run independently we don't really
只是独立运行，我们真的不
care how they're interleaved note no
不在乎别人是交错的 音符不
worries okay but as soon as they
忧虑 不错，但只要 他们
introduced sharing then then we have to
介绍分享那么接下来我们就来
be careful okay
小心好吗
so to understand how to synchronize
因此了解如何同步
threads we first need to have a clear
线程我们首先需要有一个明确的
idea of what we mean by sharing in in
的我们 所说的 做法， 只要在分享
threaded seed programs so the the answer
螺纹种子计划所以 答案
is not as simple as global variables are
是不是这么简单的全局变量
shared and stacked variables are not
共享和堆叠变量不
shared okay so with instead what we a
分享好了，所以我们有一个，而不是什么
variable X is shared if and only if
当且仅当变量X共享
multiple threads reference some instance
多线程参考一些实例
so that that variable X so if only one
使变量X，所以如果只有一个
thread is accessing a particular
线程访问特定
variable then it's it's not shared okay
可变 那么它就是 它的不共享好吗
so in order to know exactly what we mean
所以为了正是我们的意思是知道
by shared we need to answer three
通过共享我们需要回答三个
questions okay first what is the memory
问题好吗第一什么是记忆
model for threads ok second power
模型线程确定 第二电源
instances of variables mapped to memory
的变量实例 映射到存储器
and then and then third how many threads
然后，然后第三个多少个 线程
might be referencing those the instances
可能会引用这些实例
of those variables okay so we'll look at
这些变量 的 好了，我们来看看
each of those now in turn each of those
每个那些现在将每个 那些
three questions
三个 问题
okay so first is that the memory model
好了，首先 是内存模型
the conceptual model is a little bit
概念模型是一点点
different from the operational model the
从操作 模型的不同
way it really works
这样它确实有效
okay so conceptually we have multiple
好了，所以在概念上 我们有多个
threads that run in the context of a
在的上下文中运行的线程
single process okay and some of that
单进程 好一些的那
context is shared and some of its not
上下文被共享和 它 的一些 不
shared so each thread has its own
共享，每个线程都有自己的
separate thread ID stack stack pointer
单独的线程ID堆栈的堆栈指针
program counter condition codes
程序计数器条件码
general-purpose registers and then they
通用寄存器，然后他们
all share the remaining process context
所有共享剩余的进程上下文
with which data structures that the
与数据结构，所述
kernel maintains for the threads the
内核维护的线程
virtual data structures to support the
虚拟数据结构以支持
virtual memory system open files install
虚拟内存系统打开的文件 安装
signal handlers and so forth so that's
信号处理程序等等，这样的
the conceptual model and if that were
概念模型 ， 如果这是
that if that were really enforced it
如果这真的执行它
would be nice it would make things
将是很好的它将使事情
simpler for us but unfortunately in real
在实际简化了 我们无奈
life this model is not strictly enforced
生活这种模式是没有严格执行
now although register values are really
现在虽然寄存器值是真的
right the colonel maintained separate
右上校保持分离
context for the all the registers so
上下文的所有寄存器使
that that part is good but since the
那这部分是好的 ，但由于
threads share the address space a thread
线程共享地址空间中的线程
can access the memory the stack one
可以访问所述存储器中的一个堆
thread can access the stack of another
线程可以访问的另一个堆栈
thread
线
okay so although conceptually these
好了，所以虽然这些概念
stacks are separate and distinct and in
堆栈是分离和不同的，并
private they're really not and so this
私人他们 真的没有，因此这
can create some problems so here's an
可以创造一些问题，所以这里是一个
example of that we'll come back to you
例如，我们会回来给 你
later of how this one thread can access
后来的这一个线程如何 访问
the stack of another thread so here
另一个线程的堆栈所以这里
we're defining a global variable called
我们定义了一个名为全局变量
pointer which is the char star star and
指针是炭星和星
then in the main routine on declaring a
然后在声明一个主程序
local variable called messages which
局部变量称为消息，这些消息
contains it's a two element array which
包含它的两个元素的阵列，其
contains a couple strings which these
包含了两个字符串这些
will be printed out by by the threads
将由线程被打印出来
that we're going to create and then we
我们要 创建 ，然后我们
assign the global pointer to the vet to
全局指针分配给兽医
the address of the array messages okay
阵列的消息的地址行
so now pointer points to messages and
所以现在指针指向消息和
then we create in a loop we create two
那么，我们在一个循环中创建我们创建了两个
threads each of which execute this
其中的每一个线程执行这
routine called thread and and we're
程序调用线程，和我们
passing an argument so the t threads
传递参数所以吨线程
will assign a thread ID but in this case
将分配一个线程ID，但在这种情况下，
we're going to assign our own local
我们要分配我们自己的地方
thread ID by passing this sweep index
通过使此 扫描 索引 线程ID
okay so this is an example we talked
好了，所以这是 我们讲到 的 例子
about this last time it's it's kind of
关于这最后 一次，它是它是一种
it's this is perfectly okay there's no
这是这 是完全没有问题没有
race but it's it's a little weird
的比赛，但它是一个 有点怪异
because we're going to take this index I
因为我们要利用这个指标我
and cast it to a generic pointer okay
它转换为通用指针好吗
and then after we create these threads
再经过我们创建这些线程
then we'll like that the main thread now
那么 我们一定会喜欢，主线程现在
each the thread routine dereferences its
每个线程程序取消引用其
argument to get the local the local
参数，以获得当地的地方
thread ID and then it it declares a
线程ID，然后它声明
static variable count that we're going
我们要去的静态变盘点
to use to count how many times this
使用计算有多少 次这样的
thread routine is called inside of a
线程程序被调用的内
thread and then it just prints a simple
线程，然后它只是打印一个简单的
message from identifying that giving the
从识别消息给
local thread ID and then the message
局部线程ID，然后该 消息
indexed by my ID so pointer points to
我的ID索引，以便指针指向
messages so thread zero will print hello
消息，因此线程为零将打印打招呼
from foo and thread 1 will print hello
从foo和线程1将打印打招呼
from bar and then and then we increment
从酒吧，然后，然后我们 增加
the pre increment the counter variable
预增量计数器变量
okay so although it doesn't you wouldn't
好了，所以虽然它 没有你不会
you would it looks like we're accessing
你会看起来我们在访问
this global variable pointer but since
这个全局变量的指针，但由于
that was assigned to be the address of
这被分配到 的地址
the local variable on the main the main
主主局部变量
thread stack we've got this these peer
线程堆栈我们已经得到了这一点 ，这些同行
threads accessing local variables on the
线程访问的局部变量
main thread stack okay so that I just
主线程栈 好了，所以，我只是
this is not it you never want to do this
这是 不是 你永远要做到这一点
it's a very bad practice but I it's the
这是一个非常不好的做法，但我这是 在
kind of thing that can happen sometimes
之类的话， 可 有时 会发生
by accident you know if you forget that
偶然你知道，如果你忘 了
pointer actually was assigned to you
指针实际分配给您
know some some stack address okay so
知道一些一些堆栈地址好了，
that so the second question that is how
那所以第二个问题是如何
do we map variable instances to memory
我们映射变量实例存储
now we looked at this when we when we
现在我们看着这个时候我们时，我们
studied linking but let's just review
研究联系起来，但我们只是回顾
this quickly again to make sure that
再次快速这确保
it's clear to you so global variables
很明显你这么全局变量
are variables that are referenced
是被引用变量
outside of the function and virtual
的功能和虚拟的外
memory the linker when it does symbol
内存当它符号链接
resolution make sure that there's
分辨率确保有
exactly one instance of every global
每个全局的只有一个实例
variable in virtue
借助 可变
memory now local variables are declared
现在内存局部变量的声明
on the stack inside of a function
上的功能的 内部的叠层
without the static attribute and so in
没有静态属性，所以在
this case each the stack for each thread
每个这种情况下，堆叠为 每个线程
will contain one instance of that local
将包含 本地 的一个实例
variable
变量
now if variables are declared inside of
如果变量的声明里面现在
a function with the static attribute
与静态属性的功能
then the scope of that variable is
然后该变量的范围是
limited to that function meaning no
限于该功能意味着没有
other function can access it but that
其他函数可以访问它，但是
static variable is stored along with all
静态变量与所有一起存储
the other local variables so there's any
其他局部变量所以有任何
static variable declared inside of the
静态变量的内部声明
function has exactly one instance in in
函数中只有一个实例
memory and if you were to have say
内存，如果你是有发言权
multiple functions that declared the
该声明的多种功能
same a static variable with the same
同样用相同的一个静态变量
name the compiler would would
命名编译器会会
disambiguate those somehow if it would
如果它会消除歧义那些莫名其妙
it would append some kind of unique it
它会追加某种独特的 IT
would somehow make that name unique okay
会以某种方式使这个名字 唯一 好吗
okay so what recall how all these
好了，什么还记得如何将所有这些
different types of variable instances
不同类型的变量的实例
are mapped into memory Kay pointer is a
被映射到存储器凯指针是一个
global variable so there's one instance
全局变量，所以有一个实例
of pointer in the address space and it's
在地址 空间的指针，它的
stored in the in the data segment
存储在所述在所述数据段
I I and messages are examples of local
我 我和消息的本地实例
variables two main so there's one
变量两大 所以有一个
instance of these on stored on the stack
这些实例存储 在堆栈 上
of main stack and we'll denote those
主栈， 我们将表示这些
with this notation we'll say variable I
这种表示 我们会说 我 变
I dot M means variable I is stored on
我点M表示变量I被存储在
main stack and messages is stored on the
主堆叠和消息被存储在
stack of name okay now my ID is a local
名字的堆栈现在没事了我的ID是本地
variable declared affined in this thread
可变宣布仿射在此线程
routine and so there's actual sense
常规等有实际意义上
there's two of these threads there's
有两个这样的线程 有
there's now there are in memory there's
那里现在是有记忆有
there's two instances of my ID one one
还有我的ID一个一个的两个实例
for each stack okay associated with the
每个堆栈好与相关联的
stack associated with each thread so my
堆栈每个线程等等相关的我
ID t0 is stored on peer thread 0 stack
ID T0存储在对等体线程0堆
and my ID dot t1 is stored on peer
我的ID 点t1被存储在同行
thread 1 stack ok and now this counter
线程堆栈1 OK，现在这个计数器
variable the static counter variable has
变静态计数器变量
just exactly one instance in in virtual
仅仅只有一个实例中的虚拟
memory and it's in the data segment
内存和它在数据 段
along with other global variables like
随着像其他的全局变量
like pointer
像指针
okay now so the question is which of
现在没事了这样的 一个问题是这
these variables are shared and which are
这些变量是共享的，其是
not okay and so we can remember what we
不行，所以我们能记住我们
said is it's shared if it's more than
说的是，如果它比它的共享
one thread is accessing an instance of
一个线程正在访问的一个实例
that variable okay so let's let's just
该变量好了，让我们让我们 只
list all the different variables and
列出所有不同的 变量和
then let's look at each of these threads
那么让我们来看看这些线程
and see if it's referenced by that
看看它是否通过引用
thread okay so what about what about
线程好了，所以怎么样怎么样
pointer right there's just it's
指针在那里只是它的
referenced by the main thread and what
由主线程和引用什么
about peer thread zero
关于对零线
yeah it's referenced by peer thread zero
没错这就是由对等线程 零引用
right here right here and similarly for
这里就在这里，类似的还有
peach red one okay so so pointer is
桃花红一个好了，所以指针
referenced by all three threads
所有三个线程引用
now what about counts counts not
现在大概数才算数不
referenced by the main thread but it is
由主线程引用，但它是
referenced by the two peer threads now
现在 两个对等线程 引用
what about I in main that's referenced
关于我多数民众赞成引用什么主
by main of course but not by but not by
通过主菜，但不通过但不
either of the two threads
无论是两个线程
now what about messages the messages
现在怎么样的邮件消息
array okay so that's that's accessed by
排列好，这样是一个的被访问
my main and indirectly through pointer
我的主要和间接通过指针
it's referenced by each of these two
它是由每一个两个引用
peer threads now what about my ID
对线程现在来谈谈我的ID
defined in in peer thread zero okay so
在对等体定义线程在零好了，所以
that's referenced that's a local
多数民众赞成引用这是一个本地
variable so it's only referenced by peer
可变的，所以它只能通过同行引用
thread zero right it's not referenced by
螺纹零右它不是由引用
either the other threads and similarly
任一其他线程并且类似地
for for my ID and in peer threaten one
对于我的ID，并在同行中一个威胁
okay so given given that definition then
所以给出好的鉴于定义，然后
which of these variables is shared so
这些变量的共享，所以
it's really straightforward with yep
它与没错真的简单
okay so the question is does count count
好了，所以这个问题是 不计计数
as a share variable and answer is yes
作为共享变量，答案是肯定的
because because it's declared static
因为，因为它声明为static
it's there's one instance of it in in in
它 在 有它 的 一个实例 在
virtual memory and each of the threads
虚拟内存和每个线程的
references that instance okay so it's
引用该实例好了，所以它的
it's shared it's really like a global
它的共享它真的像一个全球
variable it's just a scope is limited to
变量它只是一个范围仅限于
the the it stores the same way a global
在IT卖场以相同的方式在全球
variable is but its scope is limited to
变量是但其范围限于
the function that is defined in okay so
了在好限定为使得所述函数
to determine if each one of these is
以确定是否 这些每一个 都是
whether which of these variables are
是否这些变量是
shared and which ones not we just we
共享的，哪些不是，我们只是我们
just look go across and for any any
只是看对面，任何任何去
variable with its shared by more than
其 由超过 共享变量
more than one thread then it's shared so
一个多线程那么它的共享，
pointer shared so pointer is shared
指针共享，以便指针被共享
count is not shared no no count this
计数不共享 ，不，不指望这
year because it's it's referenced by
一年 ，因为这是 它是由引用
peer thread zero and peer thread one i's
对 零 线 和同行线程一个我的
not shared because it's only referenced
不共享，因为它只是引用
by by main so
由主让
messages access referenced by all three
信息访问所有三个引用
threads so it's shared but my ID is is
线程所以它的共享，但我的ID 是被
not shared because it's only referenced
不共享，因为它只是引用
by exactly one thread okay so so pointer
正好一个线程好了，所以这样的指针
count and messages are the shared
计数和消息共享
variables in this program and the others
在这个程序中的变量和其他人
are run share yes would let the second
正在运行的份额肯定将让第二
process and over it so if you declared
过程并对其所以如果你声明
my ideas static with the second process
我的想法静态与第二过程
of overridden it yeah that would be a
的覆盖是啊，这将是一个
race okay so that would we just depend
比赛好了，所以这 将我们 只是依赖
on which which thread executed first so
在其上哪个线程执行的第一 所以
you would really wouldn't want to do
你真的不想做
that
那
okay so so we have a very clear notion
好 了，所以我们有一个非常清晰的概念
now of what we mean by sharing
现在我们通过共享的意思
so these being able to share variables
所以这些能够共享变量
like this in this ways it's very handy
像这样在这方面它是非常方便
but you can run into some really nasty
但 你可以碰到一些真是可恶
problems that are very surprising so let
是非常令人吃惊的问题，以便让
me show you an example this is a program
我告诉你一个例子，这是 一个程序
called dad count so obviously there's
叫爸爸 算上如此明显有
something wrong with this I'm giving you
有毛病这个 我给你
a little clue but what we want to do is
一点点线索，但我们想要做的是什么
we want to create we want to create a
我们要建立我们要创建 一个
bunch of threads or a number of threads
线程束或多个 线程
and each of those threads will increment
而且每个线程将增加
a global variable called count some
一个 名为 全局变量 计算一些
number of times the same number of times
次数相同 的 次数
so so we pass them the number of
所以，所以我们通过 他们的数量
iterations as the first argument and
迭代作为第一个参数，并
here's our well here's our global
这里是我们的好这里是我们全球
globally shared variable and you
全局共享的变量，而您
remember what volatile means anybody
记得挥发性意味着任何人都
remember what that means so what is
记得那是什么 意思 有啥
volatile what is volatile tell the
挥发性什么是挥发性告诉
compiler yes
编译器是
opportunity here
这里的机会
you can't access it actually you you're
你不能 真正访问你， 你
on in the right direction actually tell
在正确的方向 实际上告诉
it tells the compiler never to put that
它告诉编译器从来没有把那个
variable in a register okay so it always
在寄存器变量好了，所以它总是
it will always read that value from
它总是读取 该值
memory or store it to memory and you do
内存或者其保存至内存 和你做
that because of exactly the kind of
因为正是那种的
possibility that you mentioned so so in
你那么那么在提到 可能性
this in this case we have we create two
这在这种情况下，我们有我们创建了两个
threads but with two distinct calls to
线程但是有两个不同的调用
two pthread create each of these threads
2并行线程创建这些线程
will will run the the thread routine
将要运行的线程程序
called thread and it will pass and as an
所谓的线程，它会通过 ，并作为
argument the address of the number of
数量的参数地址
iterations that it should that it should
迭代，这应该 是它应该
iterate now remember when we were
现在迭代记得 当 我们
looking when we were passing connected
看，当我们路过连接
file descriptors if if we pass an
文件描述符如果 如果我们传递一个
address that was a race okay but in this
解决是 好的，但在这 一场比赛
case there's no race this is fine it's
情况下，有没有比赛，这是好的这是
fine just to pass the address of number
罚款只是 为了打发 号的 地址
of iterations so why is it okay in this
迭代那么，为什么在这一点，好吗
case but it wasn't okay when we were
情况下，却是不行的，当我们
passing the connected file descriptor
传递连接文件描述符
that we got from accepting to our thread
我们 从接受我们的线程 获得
routine
常规
exactly because the thread doesn't
正是因为线程 不
modify the value and that the problem we
修改的值 ，而这个问题我们
had before was that our main thread was
曾是以前， 我们的主线程
modifying that connected to script on on
改性使得连接到 脚本 上
the next call to accept but here it's
下次调用接受，但在这里它的
just the read only variable so we're
只是只读 变量，因此我们
okay but you see the how tricky the
不错 ，但你看怎么靠谱
reasoning can get right there's you
推理可以得到正确的有你
can't do pattern matching to determine
不能做模式匹配 来确定
whether you've got races or not races
你是否已经有了种族或种族不
and so you can't just say well it's
所以你不能只是 说好这是
always bad to pass the address of some
总是坏传递 的一些 地址
variable to a to a thread routine okay
变量为一个线程例行 好吗
because it's not it just depends on the
因为它不只是依赖于
context okay so in this case we're
背景好了 ，所以在这种 情况下，我们是
passing the number of iterations and to
传递迭代的 和与数
each thread and then we're waiting for
每个线程，然后我们在等待
each of those threads to finish so this
每个这些线程的完成所以这
is an examine other-- example of why you
是一个考察你为什么other--例子
need why you might want to have a non
需要你为什么会想有一个非
detached thread because you can't we
分离线程，因为你不能我们
want when we check when we check the
希望在我们检查的时候 ，我们检查
value of count we have to make sure that
计 值 ，我们必须确保
every thread is finished before we check
我们检查之前，每个线程完成
whether we got the right value or not
我们是否得到了正确的值或不
okay so we wait for each thread to
好了，所以我们等待每个线程
finish and now since we've created two
完成现在，因为我们已经创建了两个
threads each of which is incrementing
线程其中每个 递增
count Editors time we expect count to be
算上编辑时间我们预计数为
equal to two times and ITER's and if
等于两倍 和国际热核实验堆的 ，如果
it's not we print my favorite error
这不是我们打印我最喜欢的错误
message otherwise we with the value of
消息否则我们与价值
count otherwise we print okay also with
算上否则我们打印好 也
the value of count okay so now what's
算好了所以现在有什么价值
going on in the thread routine very
在线程例行 事情 很
simple it dereferences the the argument
简单，它取消引用的论据
that was passed in and stores it in the
中传递 ，并将其存储在
local copy of editors and then it loops
编辑的本地副本，然后将其循环
senators time and can increments count
参议员时间，可以增加 数
each time so and then returns so this is
每次这样，然后返回，所以这是
very innocuous what could go wrong and
很乏味什么可以去错了，
since this is threading since this is
因为这是线程，因为这是
concurrent concurrent programming
并发并发编程
especially since this threaded
特别是因为这螺纹
programming what there's the odd lots of
编程 什么 还有的零碎
subtle things can go wrong so it turns
微妙的东西 可以去错了 ，所以 它变成
out this program has a really
这一计划有一个很
this bug okay because when we run it
这个bug没关系，因为当我们运行
when we run it on a Linux box sometimes
当我们在 Linux机器 上运行它 有时
if we call it with an argument of 10,000
如果我们10000的 参数 调用它
sometimes we get the correct answer
有时我们得到正确的答案
two times 10,000 or 20,000 then the next
接下来的两次一两万然后
time we run it we get some weird number
一次，我们运行它，我们得到了一些奇怪的号码
13,000 51 completely wrong and so what
13000 51完全不对等 什么
what the heck is going on here okay
究竟发生了什么事在这里好吗
so to understand that we have to look at
所以要明白，我们来看看
the assembly language for this counter
该计数器的汇编语言
loop so that we want to we we need to
循环使我们想要 我们 ，我们需要
look at the December language for this
看看 这个十二月语言
counter loop in the thread routine so
在线程程序计数器循环，使
we'll break it up into three chunks that
我们将其拆分成三个 组块
the the first chunk is sort of getting
在第一块是那种让
ready for the loop we'll call that the
准备好循环中，我们会打电话给该
head and we'll denote we'll denote it as
头， 我们表示 ，我们将 其 表示 为
H of I for thread I and then we'll we'll
线程我和我H，则我们，我们将
we'll isolate on these three
我们将在这三个隔离
instructions that are directly related
直接相关说明
to incrementing count okay so you see
以递增数 好了，所以你看
the first instruction moves it loads the
第一指令将其加载
global of the value in global variable
全球 在全局变量的值
count into register Rd X so we'll denote
算到 寄存器 路X所以我们会代表
that as L of I next it increments RDX
， 随着I L接下来它增加RDX
we'll denote that U of I for update so
我们将 那 表示 我U表示更新 ，以便
it updates RDX and then it stores the
它更新RDX，然后将其存储
value the updated value of RDX into
重视RDX的更新值成
count
计数
okay so into the location associated
好了，进入位置 相关联
with the local global variable count and
与当地的全局 变量 计数和
and then the rest of the the rest of
然后的休息休息
this loop is getting ready for the to do
这个循环正准备 在做
the next iteration it's not directly
下一次迭代直接不
related to incrementing count so we'll
有关增加计数，所以我们会
just sort of group this all together and
只是排序组的这一起，
refer to it as T of I for Tail
称其为T的 我的 尾巴
now let's look at let's look at how this
现在让我们来看看让我们看看如何
how these two threads might be might be
如何将这些两个线程可能是可能是
executed and remember in general we
执行，一般我们记得
can't assume that there's any specific
不能假设有任何具体
interleaving so any interleaving of
交错所以任何交织
these two threads is possible no matter
这两个线程可以不管
how remote it might seem so let's look
如何远程它看起来那么让我们来看看
at one example let's say we're executing
在一个例子，让我们说，我们正在执行
on a single core so we're only going to
在单核，所以我们只打算
do one instruction at a time and in this
做一个指令的时间和在本
column will show which thread is
栏将显示哪些线程
executing
执行
so either thread 1 or thread 2 and then
所以无论是线程1或线程2，然后
we'll denote which instruction in that
我们将表示用来指示 在
thread is executing either H Lu S or T
线程 正在执行 是H 路S或T
and then this column shows the value of
然后这个列显示的值
RDX for thread number 1 and this column
RDX 线程 数 1和此列
shows the value of RDX for thread number
示出了RDX的 线程数的值
2 right and since that the kernel keeps
2右键并自该内核保持
separate copies of all the
所有的单独副本
general-purpose registers the for each
通用寄存器的每个
each thread these can be different okay
每个线程这些可以是不同的好吗
and then this last column shows the
然后这最后一列显示
value of count in memory so let's start
在内存计数的 值 ，因此，让我们开始
executing so initially count is equal to
执行所以最初计数等于
0 and thread one gets the kernel
0和线程一个得到内核
schedules thread thread 1 so it executes
调度线程的线程1，因此执行
say ch1 that has no impact on on count
说， 对 对数 没有影响CH1
then thread 1 loads the value of count
那么线程1个负载计数的值
into its copy of RDX updates it so now
到 了RDX的副本， 所以现在对其进行更新
our DX is equal to 1 and then stores
我们的DX等于1家，然后商店
that value in RDX
在RDX该值
back to count so now count is equal to 1
回算 那么现在算等于 1
now at this point the kernel decides to
就在这个 点的内核决定
schedule thread - so thread 2 begins
调度线程-所以线程 2开始
executing and when it begins executing
执行和它开始时执行
value of count is 1 so it executes H of
计数的值是1，从而它执行h的
I then it loads count into the art into
然后，我给它 装算入艺术 融入
thread 2's copy of RDX so now our DX
线2的RDX的副本， 所以现在我们的DX
equals 1
等于1
updates it now it's equal to 2 and then
更新它现在是等于 2，然后
stores that's valued back to count the
多数民众赞成看重回店来算
kernel then decides oh and then and then
内核 然后决定哦，然后再
it finishes executing the tail
在完成执行 尾
instruction and let's say we're just
指令，让我们说，我们只是
doing one iteration of this and then at
这样做的这个，然后一次迭代的
this point the kernel decides to
这一点上，内核决定
schedule thread one since thread 2 is
调度线程之一，因为线程2是
finished so thread 1 1 executes the
完成这样的线程1执行
remaining statement that it has to
剩下的说法，这有
execute and at this point both threads
执行在这一点上两个线程
are finished and count is equal to 2
完成和计数等于2
which is the value we would expect ok so
这是值我们希望确定，所以
this so this is ok and notice how so
这所以这是 确定 并注意使
this is actually this is an interleague
这其实是这是一个同盟间
that works ok we get the correct value
该工程确定我们得到正确的 值
and notice how I did a group the 3
并注意 我 是如何 做一组 3
instructions that are actually involved
这实际上涉及到的指令
and updating count together and we'll
和更新算在一起，我们将
call that we'll call those 3
调用我们会打电话给那些3
instructions a critical section and I've
指令的关键部分 ，我已经
color-coded them so you can easily keep
颜色编码，让您能轻松地
track of them all right let's look now
跟踪它们的 行 现在 让我们 看看
let's look at another another
让我们来看看另一个另一
interleaving which is feasible right but
交织是可行的，但右
in this case it results in the wrong
在这种情况下，它会导致错误的
value ok so here we start with thread 1
值确定，所以在这里我们先从 线程1
again it loads it's the value of count
再次，它加载它的计数值
into its copy of RDX updates it but then
到 了RDX的副本 更新，但随后
before I can store it the kernel decides
之前， 我 可以存储它 的内核决定
to schedule thread - so thread 2 begins
调度线程-所以线程2开始
X executing it loads count into its copy
X执行它加载到计算它的拷贝
of RDX - and notice count is still 0
RDX的-和通知数仍为0
right it's it's 1 in the value of it in
右侧是它的 1 在它的价值
thread 1 in a RDX the copy of RDX and
线程1在RDX RDX的副本
thread 1 but it hasn't been updated in
线程1，但它并没有被更新中
memory so when when when thread 2 loads
内存故当线程时负载2
its value of count now it's copy and RDX
其计值现在它的复制和RDX
is 0 now at this point the kernel
是0就在这个点的内核
reschedules thread 1 to execute so
重新排定线程1执行这样
thread 1 does it
线程1做它
or of its copy of RDX into count and
或者它的RDX的副本进入次数和
then finishes executing it's the tale
然后执行完它的故事
instruction the colonel reschedule
指令上校重新安排
thread to which picks up where it left
线程可拿起离开的地方
off it updates its copy of of count
关闭它 更新的计数的复印件
so now RDX goes from 0 to 1 and then it
所以现在RDX从0到1，然后进入它
stores that value into count so all
该值 装入计数 ，以便所有门店
we've done is we've overwritten count
我们所做的是，我们已经覆盖数
out of value 1 and we've overwritten it
出 值1，我们已经直接覆盖
with a value of 1 so when we finish
为 1的值， 所以当我们完成
execution of these two threads count has
这两个线程 的 执行 数有
the wrong value okay in the then the
错误的值的 好 ，则
general like the general thing to notice
一般像一般的一点需要注意
is you see how these critical sections
你是怎么看这些关键部分
have been interleaved right in this in
已经正确交错在这
this case this is the first the critical
这种情况下，这是第一 临界
section for thread 1 executed before the
线程1部分之前 所 执行 的
critical section for thread 2 ok but in
线程2 确定，但在 关键部分
this case the two critical sections
这种情况下，两个关键部分
interleaved okay
交错好吗
so let's see another example of that so
让我们看看那另一个例子所以
here you can see that these are
在这里你可以看到，这些 都是
interleaved so trite suggests it might
交错如此 陈腐表明，它可能
be a problem yes so I'm excusing
一个问题是，所以我原谅
well no okay so the question is would I
还有没有好 了，问题是我会
or count count if we okay it is to find
或者数数，如果我们还好是找
this volatile it didn't I yeah so that
这种不稳定的 它没有我呀，这样
that's why I mean there's actually and
这就是为什么我的意思实际上和
the compiler could have compiled this
编译器可以编译这个
code in different ways right there is
以不同的方式代码右边 有
actually an increment instruction that
实际上是一个增量指令
will increment it a variable in memory
将增加它在内存中的变量
so you could have done the compiler
所以你可以做的编译器
could have generated this this three
可能生成此这三
instruction sequence is one instruction
指令序列是一个指令
and then we wouldn't have this problem
然后我们就没有这个问题
but the problem is that it's it's it's
但 问题是，这是它的它的
loading into a register then
加载到寄存器 中，然后
incrementing and then saving so that the
递增，然后保存，以便
problem comes about because we can this
问题就来了约，因为我们可以这样
this thread can be interrupted before it
这个线程可以在 它 之前中断
finishes this three-step sequence this
完成这三步序列本
load modify store sequence yes
负载修改存储序列是
north
北
it would quit yet so it that's right
这 将又不干 ，因此 这是正确的
yeah I guess I wasn't clear it it
是的，我想我没有 清除它
prevents it from being stored
防止它被存储
permanently in a register right so it it
永久在寄存器中右所以它
if it it may have to be loaded into a
如果它可能要被装载到
register but then it'll be written back
注册，但随后 它会被写 回
okay whereas the the compiler would have
还好，而编译 器将有
the option like we've seen it with local
就像我们已经 与当地 看到 它的选项
variables right the compiler just it
变量权的编译器只是 把它
never allocates tax base it just keeps
从未分配 税基它 只是不断
that local variable in a register all
在寄存器 ，局部 变量的所有
the time okay so this preventive also
时间好了，所以这也是预防
attributed prevents the compiler from
归因防止编译器
doing that okay so let's look at another
这样做的好了，让我们来看看另一个
example
例
so here thread one starts it loads it
所以在这里线程一个开始，它加载 它
loads count into RDX then thread two
负载数到 RDX那么线程2
starts and it loads account which is
启动和加载帐户，这是
still 0 into RDX 2 updates it and then
仍是0到2 RDX更新它，然后
stores it so now count equal to 1 when
它存储所以现在算等于1时
thread 1 resumes it updates its value of
线程1恢复更新其价值
count and RDX and stores that back to
计数和RDX 并存储回
count and so again we have we have the
计数等我们再次，我们有
same problem okay so the the problem
同样的问题还行， 因此问题
here is that we're interleaving these
这里要说的是我们这些交错
these critical sections and you can
这些关键部分，你可以
understand why this is bad with a nice
明白这是为什么不好用一个漂亮的
sort of graphical technique called a
排序的图形技术的称为
progress graph
进度图
so in a progress graph if we have four n
所以，在进度图，如果我们有四个 N
threads it's an N dimensional Cartesian
线程是二维笛卡尔的N-
grid that characterizes the execution
电网为特征的执行
state space of a concurrent threaded
并发螺纹的状态空间
program so in this case each here we
节目所以在这种情况下，每个在这里我们
have two threads so it's a it's a it's a
有两个线程所以这是一个这是一个它是一个
2d coordinate system so each each axis
图2d坐标系，使每个各轴
represents the progress the execution
代表进度执行
progress of some thread so the x axis
一些螺纹的进展，以便在x轴
here is thread one and the y axis
这里是一个线程和y轴
corresponds to thread two and then each
对应于螺纹2和然后每个
one of these edges corresponds to the
这些边缘中的一个对应于所述
execution of an instruction okay so we
在指令执行好了，所以我们
start out in the initial state and then
开始时在 初始 状态，然后
the first thing we execute is h1 so
我们执行的第一件事就是H1如此
that's represented by this this arc here
多数民众赞成这个本弧这里代表
so this this position this point right
所以这个这个位置这点权
here represents the state where we've
在这里表示 ，我们已经 将 状态
executed H we finished executing h1 in
执行^ h我们执行完毕H1在
thread 1 but we haven't yet executed any
线程1，但我们还没有 执行任何
instructions in thread 2 ok so in
在线程2 OK指令，因此在
general each one of these points
一般来说，这些 点 的每一点
represents sort of the current progress
代表排序的当前进度
of the program or the execution state so
该程序 或执行 状态 的 这样
for example this this state right here
例如，这这种情况下就 在这里
represents the state where thread 1 has
表示 的状态下螺纹1具有
completed a completed l1 and thread 2 is
完成了完成的L1和线程2是
completed s2
完成S2
and now the execution of a program is
现在程序的执行是
modeled as the transition from one state
建模为从 一个状态 的过渡
to the other and there's some so from
其他 和有一些使从
from this and there's constraints on how
由此而有关于 如何 约束
on on how these these states can advance
对这些这些国家如何推进
so from this state l1s to yeah obviously
所以从这个状态L1S来呀明显
time can't go backwards right so we
时间不能倒退的权利，所以我们
can't we can't go backwards like in this
不能，我们不能倒退想在这个
direction to the left and we can't go
方向向左 ，我们不能去
down okay so we can only go to the right
下好了，所以我们只能 往右走
and up and since we're assuming that
和上， 因为我们假定
each instruction executes there's only
每个 指令 只 执行 有
one instruction executing at a time we
一条指令执行时间我们
can't go diagonally that would be two
不能斜着走那会是两个
instructions right so from l1 s to the
说明右所以从 L1 S到
next execution state is either here ifs
接下来的执行状态是不是在这里，IFS
thread one execute or here if threaded
一个线程执行或在这里 如果螺纹
thread to execute okay so you can put
线程执行好了，你可以把
all these together to form a trajectory
所有这些在一起，形成一个轨迹
which characterizes one execution of the
表征的一个执行
program right and any feasible set of
程序右和任何 可行的组
transitions from one state to the next
从一种状态过渡到下一个
corresponds to a feasible trajectory so
对应于一个可行的轨迹，从而
so for example H 1 L 1 u 1 H 2 L 2 s 1 T
因此对于例H 1升1个ü1个 小时2升2 S 1 T＆
1 u 2 u 2 s 2 and T 2
1 U 2 U 2 号第2和T 2
that's a feasible that's a feasible
这是一个可行的 ，这是一个可行的
trajectory and it's one possible it
轨迹，它是一个可能的话，
represents one possible execution or so
表示一个可能的执行左右
one set of interleavings for this
一组的交错此的
program
程序
now these lb these three these three
现在这些1b中这三这三个
instructions Lu and s that operate that
说明陆和 S是该操作
manipulate count form what we call a
操作数形式我们称之为
critical section with respect to count
对于关键部分 来算
and the idea is that instructions inside
而这个想法是，里面的说明
these critical sections would be
这些关键部分将是
computed with respect to the same global
对于计算出相同的全球
variable shouldn't be interleaved so we
变量不应该 ，所以我们 交错
can capture this geometrically by taking
可以通过利用几何抓住这个
the intersection of these critical
这些关键的交点
sections to form what we call an unsafe
部分就形成了我们 所说 的 不安全
region so in this and unsafe region is
区域所以在这和不安全的地区
is the points within an unsafe region
是不安全的区域内的点
are those those points in an execution
是在执行那些那些点
where the critical sections are being or
其中临界区正在 或
interleaved okay so for this particular
交错好了，所以这个特定
example there's four points within the
例如有内部的四点
unsafe region and if a trajectory ever
不安全的区域，如果一个曾经的轨迹
touches one of those points then we've
倒是那些点之一，那么我们已经
interleaved critical section and we're
交错的关键部分， 我们很
going to get the wrong answer okay so
会得到 错误的答案好了，
the idea is to try to stay out of these
这个想法是尽量留 出的这些
unsafe regions
不安全的地区
and if we do we say that that trajectory
如果我们这样做，我们说的是轨迹
is safe so here's an example of a
为安全 所以这里 的 一个例子
trajectory that's safe now this is okay
轨迹是安全的，现在这是好的
right this point right here is not in
权这一点就 在这里 不
the unsafe region because we haven't
不安全的区域，因为我们还没有
executed we've already executed h1 here
执行我们已经执行H1在这里
remember a point corresponds to and it's
记得有一个 点对应于和它的
the instruction that we've completed
我们已经完成了指令
that instruction so then so here we're
该指令所以后来所以在这里我们
skirting the unsafe region but it's
踢脚不安全的地区，但它
still okay so this is a safe trajectory
还是好了 ，所以这是一个安全的轨迹
we'll get the right answer for this one
我们会找到正确答案，这一个
however this trajectory is unsafe
但是这个轨迹是不安全
because it it enters the unsafe region
因为它在其进入不安全区域
at this point here and even though it
在这一点上这里即使它
quickly exits the there's an
迅速退出有一个
interleaving there that creates a
交错有一个创建
potential for a correct answer
潜在的一个正确的 答案
okay so the question is how do we
好了，问题 是我们怎么样
guarantee a safe trajectory and this is
保证安全的轨道，这是
the this is what we call synchronization
这该是我们所谓的同步
so somehow we want to we want to sort of
所以在某种程度上我们希望，我们 要排序的
configure the kernel so that'll never
配置内核， 这样永远也不会
schedule an unsafe trajectory so how do
安排一个不安全的轨迹所以怎么办
we do that
我们这样做
so somehow we we have to synchronize the
所以在某种程度上 我们，我们必须同步
execution of those threads and another
那些线程的执行和另一
way to think of this is that we we need
办法想这是 我们需要
to guarantee mutually exclusive access
保证互斥访问
to the critical sections so once once
在关键部分因此一旦一次
the kernel begins once the thread starts
内核开始，一旦线程开始
actually executing the first instruction
实际执行的第一条指令
in its critical section we don't want it
在它的关键部分，我们不希望它
to be interrupted by another thread that
由另一个线程中断是
has a similar critical section okay we
也有类似的关键部分，我们没关系
don't want it to be interrupted we don't
不 希望它被打断我们不
want one one critical section with
想一个一个关键部分
respect to certain global variable to be
对于某些 全局变量是
interrupted by another thread that has
由具有另一个线程中断
all right that's currently within that
没事这是目前内
same critical section okay sorry yes
同样重要的部分好遗憾是
question okay so the question is how
问题好了，所以问题 是怎么
likely is it that you get a correct
有可能是你 得到一个正确的
trajectory and it happens right you can
轨迹和它发生 的权利，你可以
run it sometimes you do it just depends
运行它，有时你这样做只是取决于
usually it's wrong sometimes it's right
通常这是错的，有时它是正确的
and it just depends it just depends on
它只是取决于它只是取决于
how the kernel schedule it and you can't
内核如何 安排它， 你不能
assume any particular scheduling right
假定任何特定调度权
so if you say if you want to if you want
所以，如果你说，如果你想，如果你想
to claim that you would never get the
声称你 永远不会得到
right answer then you're assuming that
正确的答案那么你就假设
the kernel is always going to schedule
内核总是会 安排
the unsafe trajectory but you can't
不安全的轨迹，但你不能
assume that in fact it doesn't sometimes
假设实际上它 并不有时
you just get lucky
你只是很幸运
and then it turns out you have to you
然后事实证明， 你有 你
have to call this function with a pretty
必须调用此函数一个漂亮
big number in order to trip it up it so
为了 使绊 了这么大数量
the and it makes sense right it's
将是有意义的权利是
usually what what the kernel does is
通常什么什么内核所做的是
that we can only schedule
我们只能安排
we can only reschedule a thread you know
我们只能重新安排你知道一个线程
swap it out and schedule another thread
换出来，并安排另一个线程
in when there's some exception okay so
在当有一些例外， 所以没关系
that that passes control back to the
其将控制传递 回
kernel
核心
so these exceptions are in two forms
所以这些异常有两种形式
either calling assistant making system
无论是叫助理制作系统
calls so that'll that'll trap into the
调用，以便将那将陷 入
kernel so that's a form of exception or
内核所以这是例外的形式 或
the timer interrupt goes off which
定时器中断 熄灭这
transfers control back to the back to
控制转移回回
the kernel so the timer the timer is
内核所以计时器定时器
going off on intervals of like
在间隔会去像
milliseconds right so if we're just
毫秒右所以，如果我们 只是
doing one iteration in each thread when
在每个线程的时候做一个迭代
a thread gets executed the chances are
一个线程得到执行的机会
very low that the timer is going to go
非常低的定时器会 去
off while that thread is executing you
而线程执行 你关闭
know it's its little loop but as we and
知道这是它的小环但我们和
we're not making any system calls right
我们没有做任何系统调用 权
so there's there's nothing though
所以有没有什么的，虽然
there's nothing we're not we're not
没有什么我们不是 我们不是
we're not we're not passing control back
我们不是我们 不是通过 控制回
into the kernel ourselves so the only
到内核必须让自己的 唯一
way the kernel is going to get access is
办法内核是会得到 访问
if the timer interrupts goes off so if
如果定时器中断熄灭，所以如果
we're doing a very small number of
我们正在做一个非常 小的数目
iterations the probability that you know
迭代以你知道的概率
so here's the timer interval it's going
所以这里的它会定时间隔
off at intervals like this here this the
关在这里这个是这样的时间间隔
probability we have to
概率， 我们必须
that's thread would have to have been
这就是线程将不得不一直
scheduled right before a timer interrupt
定时器中断前 右计划
will go off or to interrupt that one or
将关闭或中断一个或
two iterations so it turns out we have
两个迭代 所以事实证明，我们有
to schedule we have to call this
安排 我们必须调用这个
function with a lot of within ITER's
与 ITER 中 的 很多功能
being fairly large so that the the
是相当大，使得该
probability of the timer interrupts
定时器中断的 概率
going off during that during that during
在那段 期间会关闭
that loop but gets increasingly large
该循环，但得到越来越大
that makes sense
这是有道理的
so the classic solution from this comes
所以从这个经典的解决方案来
from the early 1960s one of the most
从最早期的20世纪60年代 一个
famous computer scientists a Dutchman
著名计算机科学家荷兰人
named Edgar Edgar Dykstra and he came up
名为埃德加·埃德加·戴克斯特拉，他想出了
with the the classical first solution to
与经典的第一 溶液中以
this problem which is what we're going
这个问题是我们要什么
to look at it it's still the first it's
看着它，它仍然是 第一它的
fundamental and very general purpose and
基本的和非常通用 和
there's there's been many iterations and
还有的存在一直 多次迭代和
variations on this idea but semaphores
这个想法，但信号灯的变化
were the first and classic solution
分别为第一和经典的解决方案
which we'll look at okay so a semaphore
我们来看看好了，所以信号灯
is that is a non- global integer that's
是一个非全球整数这
used as a synchronization variable by
用作由同步变量
two to kernel functions called PM z our
两内核函数称为 PMž我们
two system calls called P and V
两个系统调用称为 P和V
these P&V or correspond to the Dutch
这些P＆V或对应于荷兰
words but we just just we just call them
话，但我们才刚刚我们 只是给他们打电话
P and V right you just have to learn
你只要 学会 P和V权
what what they do so each of these takes
他们做了什么什么，所以每一种需要
as an argument of a semaphore and the P
作为信号 和P的一个参数
operation has the following semantics if
操作有以下语义如果
if s is non zero then decrement it by 1
如果s是非零然后减 1 它
and return immediately and this test if
并立即返回这个 测试，如果
it that it's non zero and the decrement
它，它的非零和减量
occur atomically so so they'll never be
发生原子那么那么他们永远是
interrupted however if s is zero then
然而打断如果s 为零 ，则
suspend this thread until s becomes non
暂停本线程，直到S成为非
zero and that thread then is restarted
零和线程，然后重新启动
by a V operation okay so if T if the
通过V 操作没关系所以如果T，如果
semaphore is zero P just blocks it just
信号量是零和 P只是阻止它只是
gets suspended until it gets restarted
被暂停，直到它被重新启动
by a V operation and then after it
通过V 操作，然后它经过
restarts the P operation now can
现在重新启动P操作可以
decrement s by one and return control to
减量S按一个和 返回控制
the caller
呼叫者
okay the Z operation just increments s
还好在Z操作只值被增加了
by one and this increment unlike that
一个和该增量不像
count plus plus that we looked at just
算上加再加，我们望着眼前
looked at that increment occurs
看着那个增量出现
atomically okay so it can never be
原子好了，所以它绝不可能
interrupted and then after it increments
中断，然后它增加后
s it checks to see if there's any any
s时，检查，看看是否有任何任何
threads that are blocked in a pea
被阻止在 豌豆线程
operation so you can think of the kernel
操作以便你 能想到 的内核
just keeps a queue of threads that are
只是让那些线程队列
blocked in a pea operation and the V
阻塞在豌豆操作和V
operation after it increments s it
操作它增加后 的IT
checks that queue for any any threads
该排队任何任何线程检查
that were blocked because when they did
这被阻止，因为当他们
the pea operation the semaphore was zero
豌豆操作信号量为零
and then it restarts exactly one of
然后重新启动正好一个
those threads in some indeterminate
在一些不确定的那些线程
order okay in some worker that you can't
订购一些工人没关系， 你不能
you can't assume it just picks one using
你不能假设它只是使用一个挑选
some some selection algorithm and it and
有的一些选择算法，它和
then it it it unblocked the suspended
然后将其它它畅通 悬浮
the suspended process which then
挂起的进程，然后
completes its pea operation by
完成它的豌豆操作由
decrementing yes
是递减
okay this seems like really simple but
好吧，这看起来很简单 ，但
it can be kind of hard to get your head
它可以 是 一种很难 让你的头
around the first time you see it so
第一次 在 你 身边 看到这么
there any questions about PMD okay so
有关于PMD任何问题好了，
that the key idea that the assembly
该核心理念， 大会
these definitions of P and V is that it
P和V的这些定义是，它
imposes an invariant on semaphores
规定了信号量不变
called the semaphore invariant which is
所谓信号灯不变的是
s which is that for a semaphore s being
S的是，对于 一个信号量 重塑：
operated on by P and D operations s is
操作上通过P和D操作 s是
always greater than or equal to zero
总是大于或等于零
okay
好的
and that doesn't seem very exciting but
而这 似乎 并不 非常令人兴奋的 ，但
it turns out that this is a very useful
事实证明，这是 一个非常有用的
property that will allow us to enforce
物业，这将使我们执行
mutual mutual exclusion on these
这些相互互斥
critical sections so the T and V
所以 T和 V 的关键部分
operations are provided by P threads in
操作由P个线程中提供
the form of three functions there's a
三个函数的形式有一个
Semin it functions which initializes the
肖明它的功能它初始化
semaphore to some value
信号量一定的价值
okay so semaphore is can be initialized
好了，信号量可以初始化
to any any value greater than or equal
到大于 任何任意值 或等于
to zero some weight is the T operation
到零一些重量是T操作
and some post is the V operation okay
有的岗位是V 工作好吗
and because I'm old-school
因为我是老派
I provide wrapper functions for those in
我为那些在提供包装函数
the in your si si PP dot H file called P
中称为P的硅Si PP点.h文件
and D okay it's also more compact to
和D 还好 它也更紧凑
okay so recall our recall our buggy
好了，所以记得我们的召回 我们的越野车
program called bad counts II which was
程序调用坏计数II这 是
giving us the wrong answers for count so
让我们为计数错误的答案，所以
how do we use semaphores to fix this
我们如何使用信号量来解决这个问题
program so the basic idea is to create a
节目所以基本的想法是创建一个
semaphore which is initialized to 1 and
信号量，其被初始化 为1， 并
so by definition we'll call any
因此按照定义 ，我们会打电话给任何
semaphore which is initialized to 1
信号量，其被初始化为1
that's used for to provide mutual
多数民众赞成用于 相互提供
exclusion we'll call that a mutex okay
排除我们会打电话给一个互斥体 好吗
this goes back to the early Dijkstra
这可以追溯到 早期的Dijkstra
papers so we'll associate a unique mutex
论文，所以我们唯一的关联互斥
initialized to 1 for each shared
初始化为1，为每个共享
variable in our program ok so in this
变量在我们的程序 确定，所以在这
case count we have count so we have one
案例数我们已经算 ， 所以 我们 有一个
shared variable that we're concerned
共享变量，我们关心
about so we'll we'll create one new text
约所以我们，我们将创建一个新的文本
that will call mutex and then you
将调用互斥体，然后你
surround the critical section with
围绕与关键部分
respect to count with a pea you call PE
对于与你叫 PE 豌豆数
then you execute the critical section
那么你执行关键部分
and then you call V
然后调用V
now there's some there's some
现在有一些有一些
terminology we'll use and we talked
术语我们将使用我们谈
about semaphores so a binary semaphore
关于信号灯所以二进制信号
is is the semaphore value is always 0 1
是在所述信号值始终0 1
and then a mutex is this sort it is a
再一个互斥这算哪门子 它是一个
binary semaphore that's being used to
多数民众赞成在使用 二进制 信号
for mutual exclusion the P operation is
互斥P 操作是
called locking the mutex will refer to a
称为加锁互斥将指
V is sometimes unlocking or releasing
V被有时解锁或释放
the mutex and if a process is holding
互斥并且如果一个进程保持
the mutex then that means it's been
互斥那么这意味着它已经
locked but not not not released so
锁定但不是不可不释放，
mutexes and binary semaphore s are
互斥体和二进制 信号 s 为
always initialized to 1
总是被初始化为1
accounting semaphore and the mutex is
会计旗语和互斥
used for mutual excuse exclusion but you
用于相互 排斥 的借口 ，但你
can also use semaphores to count sort of
还可以使用信号量来 排序 的 数
events in the system and oftentimes for
在系统中， 常常事件
those accounting semaphores have sort of
那些占信号灯有几分
non non values that are greater than 1
是大于 1 的非非值
okay so for mutual exclusion we'll do to
好了， 为互斥，我们将做的
fix our program we create a new program
解决我们的节目，我们创建一个新 程序
called good count c and here we
所谓的好计数C在 这里 ， 我们
initialize a mutex we create a mutex and
初始化一个互斥体，我们创建一个互斥体和
initialize it to 1 and then we surround
它初始化到1，然后我们环绕
the the critical section which is the 3
的关键部分，其是 3
assembly language instructions embodied
汇编语言指令体现
that implements this count plus plus
实现这个数加上加
instruction we surrounded it with a P
指令我们 用P 包围它
followed by it via V and if we do that
通过V加上它，如果我们这样做
we always get the right answer
我们始终得到正确的 答案
but you know P and D our system calls so
但你知道 P和D 我们的系统调用 等等
there's overhead associated with these
还有的开销与这些相关的
so they're not free in fact they're
所以他们不是事实上 它们是 免费的
orders of magnitude this program runs on
数量级这个程序运行上
orders of magnitude slower than the
数量级比慢
incorrect buggy version all right so so
不正确马车版本没事 如此如此
why do these mutexes work so here we've
为什么这些互斥体工作，所以这里我们
got a progress graph now where we've
搞到现在的进度图，我们已经
we've decorated our program with P and V
我们装饰我们的计划与P 和 V
operations so we put the P before the
操作所以 我们把在P前
critical section we execute the critical
关键的部分，我们执行的关键
section and then we call V and now if
部分，然后我们称之为V和现在如果
you were to look a number P and Z P
你看 一个 数P和ZP
increments the sum of P decrement the
递增P的总和递减
sign before V increments the semaphore
签署 为单位递增 信号灯 前
so if you were just to look at the value
所以，如果你只是 看价值
of that semaphore for every point in the
该 信号在每一个点的
execution state space you'd get these
执行状态空间， 你会得到这些
you'd get these values so here we
你会得到这些值，以便我们在这里
initialize the semaphore at the origin
在原点初始化信号
we initialized it to 1 so the value of
我们把它初始化为1这样的价值
of our semaphore at the origin is 1 and
我们 在原点 信号 为1，
let's say we just move along so we're
比方说，我们只是待着 所以我们
just executing thread 1 so after H 1 the
刚刚执行的线程1小时1后如此
semaphore is 1 we do the PE the
信号为1，我们做PE的
semaphore is 1 so P just decrement sit
信号量是1因此P只是坐在递减
and and proceeds so now the semaphore
和现在前进因此该信号
value becomes 0 and it remains zero
值变为0，并将其保持 为零
until we execute the V and when we
直到我们执行V和，当我们
finished executing the V the semaphore
完成执行在V信号量
now is is 1 again ok so if we go through
现在的问题是是1再次确定 ，所以，如果我们经历
a similar reasoning if we look at the
类似的道理，如果我们看一下
trajectory to get to any point in this
轨迹去了任何一点
state space so let's say let's say this
状态空间让我们说，让我们说这个
point right here so to get there we
点这里 所以 到那里我们
could we could execute thread 1 up to
可能我们可以执行的线程1到
this point finish the l1 and then
至此完成 L1，然后
execute h 2 and then do the at this
执行H 2，然后做这个
point the semaphore is 0
指向信号量是0
and then tea decrements the semaphore so
然后茶递减信号使
now it's minus one but that's that's
现在是零下之一，但就是这样的
impossible
不可能
that can't happen because P blocks
不能发生，因为P个块
remember if if the semaphore is 0 P
记住，如果如果信号量是0 P
blocks it doesn't decrement it okay so
块不 好吗 递减这么
the semantics of the T operation
第t操作的语义
prohibits this this this transition it
禁止这这这是转型
prohibits this transition to the state
禁止在转变到状态
whereas semaphore is zero to a state
而信号量是零的状态
where it would be minus 1 and so it
哪里会减 1， 所以它
creates it creates what we call a
创建它创造了我们所说的
forbidden region so these these points
禁止区域所以这些这些点
in the state space where the semaphore
在状态空间， 旗语
would have a value of minus 1 are
将有减1的值
infeasible that can never be reached by
不可行，可从来没有 达到
the definition of of T and V okay so
的T和V的 行，从而定义
this this forms a forbidden region
此这 形成的禁区域
around the unsafe region and in doing so
周围的不安全区域，这样做
provides mutually exclusive access to
提供互斥访问
thee to the critical sections in each
你向在每个临界区
thread okay so if so this is the
线程好了，所以如果是这样，这 是
fundamental reason why T's and V's can
根本原因T公司和V的CAN
be used to provide mutually exclusive
被用来提供互斥
access
访问
so any questions on this I explained it
因此， 在这个任何问题 我解释过
so clearly that there's no questions
这么清楚，有没有问题
all right good well you get to go you
没事不错嘛你 去你
get to get to leave early then work on
获得去年初离开的话，在工作
your Mallik lab all right so we'll see
您Mallik实验室没事 ，所以我们会看到
you Monday we're going to look at some
你周一我们要看看 一些
sort of some advanced topics this is
排序的一些高级的主题，这是
like her first introduction to
像她第一次接触
synchronization on Tuesday we'll look at
周二同步，我们来看看
more advanced topics in synchronization
在同步更高级的主题
in ways ways that you can use semaphores
在方式方法，你可以使用信号灯
for to provide other other more
为提供其他其他更
interesting other interesting kinds of
有趣的其他有趣的种
synchronization for your programs okay
为你的程序的同步好吗